NIDHI THAKOR

Ahmedabad, 380060 | 816 096 8494 | nidhithakore1@gmail.com

Profile

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nidhi-thakor-0a75a8a9

Professional Summary

Goal-oriented Human Resources Specialist with 9.8 years of experience in payroll management and policy implementation. Strong financial acumen with demonstrated success in budget development and adherence. Accustomed to analyzing company needs and developing long-term solutions to meet personnel objectives.

Skills

- Wages and salary
- Payroll Management
- Talent management
- Benefits and compensation
- Factory Act & Industrial Act

- Legal Compliances & Benefits
- Pre-Employment Screening
- Leadership
- Performance Management
- HR policies

Work History

SENIOR HR 12/2018 to Current

BRAIN TECLABS PVT LTD - AHMEDABAD, GUJARAT

- Maintained optimal staffing levels by tracking vacancies and initiating recruitment and interview processes to identify qualified candidates.
- Acted as staff member advocate, encouraging and supporting Executives to identify and resolve conflicts.
- Liaised between management and employees to deliver conflict resolution, alleviate problems and interpret compensation and benefits policies.
- Completed human resource operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees.
- Planned, monitored and appraised employee work results by training managers to coach and discipline employees.
- Reviewed existing policies and procedures to make recommendations for enhancing work productivity, recruitment, hiring processes and talent management.
- Calculated deductions and processed payroll for employees.
- Uploaded time records into Saral and made adjustments to create accurate database for

- payroll processing functions.
- Independently maintained 95% accuracy in transferring correct data from payroll spreadsheets into Saral system.
- Performed calculations in overtime, vacation and sick hours to provide accurate data to payroll processing database.
- Collaborated with legal and compliance teams to review paperwork, obtain feedback and procure available information for new training processes.
- Manage PMS by various processes.

SENIOR HR & ADMIN EXECUTIVE

07/2017 to 11/2018

AKHANDJYOT ENERGY PVT LTD – AHMEDABAD, GUJARAT

- Direct Personal, Training & Labor relations Activities.
- Advice managers on organizational policy matters and recommended needed changes.
- Identify staff vacancies and recruit, interview and selection applicants.
- Serve a link between management and employees by handling questions, interpreting and administering contracts, and helping resolve work related problems to foster positive environment.
- Established new application protocols that increased interview applicant quality.
- Prepare Compensation Structures.
- All Increment related activities.
- To issue various letters like offer letter, appointment letter, confirmation letter, increment letter, transfer letter, Absenteeism notice, warning letter, showcase notice, experience/service certificate, relieving letter, etc.
- Met with new hires to explain benefits, guidelines, and procedure.
- Looking over all HR & Administrative activities and canteen handling.

HR & ADMIN HEAD 04/2015 to 09/2016

DIGITAL ENGINEERING PROJECTS PVT LTD – AHMEDABAD, GUJARAT

HR Executive 07/2013 to 03/2015

DIGITAL ENGINEERING PROJECTS PVT LTD – AHMEDABAD, GUJARAT

Junior HR Executive 01/2012 to 06/2013

DIGITAL ENGINEERING PROJECTS PVT LTD – AHMEDABAD, GUJARAT

Education

03/2013 **Bachelor of Commerce**: Accounting

Gujarat University - Ahmedabad, GJ

Master Of Business Administration: Human Resources Management 12/2017

Sikkim Manipal University - Ahmedabad, GJ

Certifications

CPCA - Certified Professional Computer Accounts

- December'2012

- Other HR Certification courses from LinkedIn Learning.
- Human Resources Strategy and Facility Management from Udemy.

Additional Information

Date of Birth: 14/02/1993

Hobbies: Book Reading, Travelling, Food.

Language Fluency:

Gujarati: 85% English: 80% Hindi: 80%